Something really super exciting.
Local supermarkets are nice.
That's good.
It's cheap, so there you go again.
What is this?
I think I might have found it through the entrance.
What is this couple ramen?
Dream Noodles
face
immediately
I'll get out of your way.
Hello. - Hello.
Are you the manager?
President.
Mr. President.
You, Mr. Sato.
please remember me
excuse me for disturbing (interrupting) you
I'd love to have you back as soon as possible.
When I came to Onaga Bay before, Mr. Takahashi
I found a supermarket called "Youya" very interesting.
I heard that you really want me to go.
I couldn't go then, but this time
Thank you.
I've always been curious.
Do you have any recommendations on which section?
All of them.
I'd recommend all of them.
Especially fisheries or marine products.
The rest is side dishes.
Special Features.
Let's go have a look.
I'd love to buy some meat and go home.
We'll even ship it to you.
Can you ship?
Let's get some hormones and go home.
amazing (e.g. of strength)
excuse me for disturbing (interrupting) you
Hello, I'm sorry to bother you.
anus (typically used in a vulgar, sexual sense)
Anko from Hormone Owner
Heh, I want to buy it.
This was picked this morning.
This probably landed about an hour or two ago.
It's a market right in front of us.
I know.
That's the strength of the fisheries section here.
I think it's probably the top level in Japan.
We buy it directly from the fishery.
In that auction.
yeah
Then it's within a 5 minute drive.
Yes, sir.
Processing soon.
Wow, that's great.
I'm going out on the sales floor.
I'll probably be on the sales floor in about 30 minutes to an hour.
Heh.
Freshness.
Can you ship these as well?
We can ship.
Hey, I think I'll ship it out.
I wonder if my mom would be mad at me for shipping it out of the blue.
Here's anko (bean paste).
internal (e.g. disk)
This is more than just sending it as is.
Our service will take care of it.
Ready to eat.
Also, there is such a thing as shipping as is.
Do you think it will last until tomorrow night or something?
It's totally holding up.
Then I'll definitely buy one and take it home.
Hey, I'm having a lot of fun and it's really big.
This is also in my stomach right now.
This is also the one that got all of them.
Isn't the fish cheap?
I can buy it at a discount.
We are happy to offer it to you at a discount.
I've never had any luck with fish.
Most of the time when I go there, it's already nighttime.
We're almost out of fish.
With this kind of devastation.
It's such a devastation.
What shall we buy for fun?
This area is already up in Ishinomaki.
I'm wrapping it around the floor.
It's up in Ishinomaki.
I want to get it tomorrow when I get home.
This one is a delicatessen.
side dish
The best recommendation is
Kayo's delicatessen in Nagayako-cho
Kayo's side dish
My mother died in the earthquake.
Yes, sir.
born and raised in a small and medium-sized house, with a long upbringing
It's rather strong in flavor.
I'm curious to see what the chief tastes like.
Inherit it all the way.
Our staff handmade everything.
Then the one called Kayo-chan...
My mother.
It's your mother.
Leave this behind.
I just got the name.
I know.
Hello. - Hello.
greeting used when entering someone's home
Uh, mom, I'm sorry to bother you.
I'm going to have a taste of my mother's flavor, then.
What should I do?
Wow, it looks delicious and smells so good!
Wow, yakisoba looks delicious!
Because, you know, I'm like, wow, I'm like a greedy woman.
When I was viking, I packed my pans.
Really?
Everyone is panting.
Yea. But, you see, so are the others.
Not at all.
Thank you very much.
How about something else?
I'll have some o-hagi, then.
Handmade.
Great. Okay, let's have this one. Wow.
Wow, that's nice. Oh, wait a minute. You're really lost, aren't you?
But fresh fish, let's send them. Home.
Octopus head?
Eh, I want an octopus head.
I love octopus heads so much!
Octopus head and
We can send this to you, too.
I can do it.
with this
eating something raw
I want to send it to you.
with this
I'll send this to you.
And then there are the sweets.
these two
To your home.
I'd like to eat the one I bought.
expression of gratitude before meals
very large
How's it going?
Tender chicken, delicious.
It tastes like home. My grandma had this kind of taste.
dear
yeah
I really don't want to eat rice on yakisoba.
Even though it's delicious.
That was a delicious meal (said after meals)
Did Hiroki's mother, Kayo, originally focus on prepared foods?
Not really.
Mother.
Probably made it at home, though.
This supermarket itself on the day the 11th year after the earthquake started.
If it's been 10 years since March 11, 2011, then March 11, 2021, here's where the decade ended.
The next day, March 12, they said it opened at the start of its 11th year.
I see.
I guess the disaster area and the survivors are separated by 10 years, so opening this place on that new day was also a target.
With Lisa.
Why are you doing it in English?
start
But it's great, but so are the people of the city. I'm sure this supermarket is a source of comfort for them.
It can be made in the refrigerator as it is.
I felt that I had to continue to be.
Well, even on a weekday, there were quite a few customers, and I thought it was really nice to feel at home in the city.
But I will definitely come back.
Yes, sir.
please remember me
Welcome to the Dragon's Palace of Kanagawa
Yay! Fun!
Let's get going. Sorry to interrupt.
Thank you.
Hi there, hello there, sorry to bother you.
Oh, there it is. Are you at the crime scene? Are you on site?
I like something.
special approval
yeah! (sound made by ducks, geese, crabs, etc.)
There you go.
The rest.
Yay!
I'll be there.
Oh my God, it looks so delicious.
Here they come.
That's great.
ta-dah!
Can I take your picture?
Wow!
expression of gratitude before meals
I really don't know where to start!
Well, let's start with the shellfish.
expression of gratitude before meals
delicious
Fresh.
You can tell the shellfish is incredibly fresh.
I feel like I'm eating the ocean.
That aroma, flavor and texture is so fresh.
Yes, the texture is... amazing.
fatty tuna meat (esp. belly, an expensive cut of tuna)
expression of gratitude before meals
The fat is amazing.
sweet
Here is the whale that Mr. Okase of Konagawa is pushing for
Konagagawa itself is a whale.
Yes, yes, yes, it's a whaling base.
expression of gratitude before meals
Hmmm... not a habit at all.
It's soft.
Mmm, yummy!
Goes well with ginger.
Are whales often served in school lunches?
Yes, it's served as it is in local school lunches.
In case you're wondering, whales are expensive and I think it's once or twice a year.
When I was a kid, we used to have whale for school lunch.
I don't know, I often get a chance to eat whale bacon or something like that.
You don't get to eat whale nuts very often.
Sashimi is not served at school lunches that often.
that's so, isn't it
Fried whale with grated daikon and other ingredients.
That kind of whale sleet, or something like that, is also available.
Then, since I've already eaten this today, I can finally say that I've come to Onagawa.
I want to eat in bulk.
The Last Bite
delicious
That was a delicious meal (said after meals)
It was delicious.
eating everything (on one's plate, etc.)
previous conviction
I couldn't eat a bowl of rice with a tail.
I got the burger one.
It's been a very long time since I've had a bowl of rice with a tail.
Consistently delicious!
You ate.
That was a delicious meal (said after meals)
in that case
incidentally
the long tail end of a butterfly
was said to be in the direction of the station.
what do you think?
I want to see you.
Are you sure?
if you like
Is he an interesting character?
Hardness
It's squishy.
not hard at all
He is a guitarist himself.
I'm in a band.
Is it ongoing?
Ocho is in a band with Chomin.
amazing (e.g. of strength)
butterfly
I've been invited too.
He asked me to play the violin.
Are you doing it?
I'll be touched a little.
amazing
They wanted strings.
It's great.
He's a soft person like that.
Please come and meet us!
please
I would like to have
I didn't say they were around here.
I wonder where. I wonder where.
What's that? Is that him over there? That's a butterfly!
What? Wait a minute.
Is he there?
Butterflies, right?
There's a way to make an appearance like that.
Butterfly.
butterfly
Hello. - Hello.
I knew it. Butterflies.
I thought I made a little mistake once.
No, that was definitely the butterfly.
I'm on my way.
What are you doing, butterflies?
I'm waiting.
I'll be right there.
plunking
Hello. - Hello.
It's been a long time.
Welcome to the site.
greeting used when entering someone's home
The Mayor is as delightful as ever.
Are you playing?
It makes me feel amazingly happy.
Thank you.
It really is a panoramic view.
When we did the Koko Machi Biraki in March 2015.
We could have Momoko-san do a live concert on the hill.
I'm sorry to have disturbed you.
At that time, the tempo was not yet this way.
Although everyone has visited us many times since then
It's really beautiful again.
I have the support of many people in various ways.
We can all color together again.
When I say with color, I mean with color.
It was all of you who colored us in that situation at that time.
No, no, no, no, no.
That's not true.
You have welcomed us through the toughest of times.
We also received a lot of hospitality.
I really still remember it vividly.
Back then, it was still all dirt.
There was a lot of debris.
It's a big evolution.
It stretches straight out to sea from here.
You're stretching toward the sea.
As this road and the first sunrise rises from the middle of this
This road is designed.
This year, too.
Quite a number of them every year.
amazing (e.g. of strength)
this is the way it should be
Like a short YouTube video that says, "Here's what's going on here.
So here's the thing.
This is already too much of an omen.
This year, we've already had 1,500, 600, almost 2,000 people.
More than 2,000 people.
I see.
It's now firmly established as the spot for the first sunrise of the year.
Well, I was aiming for it, but of course.
I see.
But I'm pretty sure I'm not the only one who's a fan.
He said he went to Onagawa.
I saw it on social media and stuff.
something
I'm not from the city at all, but thankfully they called me a friend, and it made me want to say, "Isn't our town really nice?
That's because Renian told me he was your friend.
I'm really kind of happy. The scenery is nice, the air is good.
There are a lot of stores like this, and there are these butterflies, so, yes, butterflies, I heard that you have a band.
I'm a bit of a recluse. I'm sure that's not true.
It was quite true.
The reason for this... well, actually, I'm not saying it's true, but...
I think it was that first time that you came over with the debris stocking, the high school students.
There was a band in our town I think it was at that time there was a band in our town I think it was at that time there was a band in our town by high school students
The kids in the band asked me to play one song with them.
What's the song about? It's called "Eager, the Warrior of Rias," and it's a local showcase.
I remember that theme song.
I'm glad I remember that theme song.
It's been about 20 years since I played in front of anyone.
I started playing with the local youth band, and then I started mixing with the local youth band.
I'm starting my own band now. I guess I got a taste for it.
Yeah, yeah, so if I hadn't been approached by a high school student at that time...
I might not have done it... now.
That's fate, too, isn't it?
I knew that Momokuro-chan's covers and such would be a good idea.
I'd love to!
No, really?
I knew it was mainly guitar, right?
I don't know if it's too long, like in and in and in and in.
Farewell and thank you for knowing!
But we also have songs that we wrote with this city in mind.
Or the song "Virtual Dystopia.
Ooh.
I didn't know that story.
Ah, but...
Oh, I didn't know that.
I just figured it out for the first time.
It's settled.
So let's do it.
We would love to have you do it!
Good.
Yes, sir.
I hope Neemonokusen will be pleased.
Performance.
Oh yeah, remember the first time we set off fireworks?
hello (on phone, replying to "moshimoshi")
At that time, I was watching with Mononokunokku the whole time.
That's right, look up at the night sky and go to sleep
In the rubble... in the middle of nowhere... with fireworks going off...
All of the colorful Mononokusan were the right color.
a-ha-ha-ha (laughing loudly)
And you're looking at them like this the whole time.
grunting or groaning sound
I remember with many thoughts.
Uh-oh.
grunting or groaning sound
I feel all kinds of time passing.
that's so, isn't it
yeah
So, I'm really enjoying my day, but...
From now on.
Yes, sir.
I look forward to having you as a friend.
Well, it's my pleasure, too, from your friend.
From your friends
(after a noun) used when calling out to someone
I was wondering if I could call myself a friend now.
Well, it's my pleasure.
We apologize for the inconvenience, but ...
I will now proudly identify myself.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Are you sure you want to be friends?
It's okay.
Thank you for your continued support.
Thank you for most of it.
Thank you for your time today.
We'll be waiting for you again.
Yes, thank you very much.
in that case
In the vicinity of Koyagawa Station
I spent a whole day in the area around Koyagawara Station, and I enjoyed it to the fullest.
I feel at home whenever I come here.
I'm back...that's what I'm feeling...
I was able to eat Onagawa rice bowl safely this time, and I also felt that Onagawa is a warm town where I could stay.
I visited the factory again for the first time in many years.
I had the opportunity to try my hand at making pottery, and I made many new discoveries, and I even got to say hello to the mayor of the town.
I think we had a lot of fun together, and I'm looking forward to visiting Onagawa again as friends, so please come and visit us.
Please, Onagawa, that's enough!
something that has happened non-stop
Bye-bye. Thank you very much. It was fun.